### Contact

tommyher424@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/tommy-her-246746222 (LinkedIn)

## Top Skills

Web Development
React.js
Python (Programming Language)

#### Certifications

AWS Certified Developer – Associate

# Tommy Her

Full stack JavaScript Developer (React, Node, Angular, Next)
Ravena

## Summary

With a decade of experience as a web developer, SEO strategist, and software engineer, I know what it takes to build a successful website from the ground to effectively nurture and convert your target market. I am experienced in responsive web development using React, Angular, Vue, Node, Express, Redux, Next, JavaScript, TypeScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, GraphQL, custom APIs, eCommerce, SEO, and cloud platforms.

I develop unique web apps/websites that drive considerably more sales, results, and leads to your business than the industry average. I have worked in many different industries such as professional services, retail, wine, technology, real estate, entertainment, and healthcare.

#### Tech Stacks:

- React, Angular, Vue, Next, Node, Express, Tailwind, Material, Bootstrap, jQuery, JavaScript, TypeScript
- PHP, Laravel, Python, Django
- GraphQL, RESTful API, GraphQL, 3rd party API integration
- MongoDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL
- Amazon Web Service

I meticulously manage all website projects from defining scope, market research, and concept development to your website launch and web maintenance support so you stay informed and on track every step of the way. The majority of my clients have been with me for many years because I am very passionate about web development.

In my personal life, I enjoy spending time with friends and family, as well as almost any outdoor activity.

## Experience

Elevation Ten Thousand Full-stack Software Developer July 2018 - 2021 (3 years) Latham, NY

 Involved in the complete Software Development Life Cycle including gathering Requirements, Analysis, Design, Implementation, Testing, and Maintenance. Implemented user interface guidelines and standards throughout the development and maintenance of the website.

Techs used: React, Node, Express, Angular, Vue, Next, Tailwind, RESTful API, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, AWS

Vibrant Brands Web Developer 2016 - June 2018 (2 years) Albany, NY

•Tested and implemented the swagger UI docs/routes, for front-end use and back-end development and used Fast API and some request library/decorators for faster development to dispatch front-end JSON type schema for delivery of SQL, CSV files, and using MySQL.

Techs used: React, Node, Express, Angular, Redux, RESTful API, MongoDB, AWS

Upside Collective Javascript Developer 2013 - 2015 (2 years) Albany, NY

 Responsible for creating new features with React, using React Hooks, and the latest ES6 features. Used Redux for state management and optimized state as needed. Worked with the team with Git and Did Code Reviews periodically. Used AWS cloud desktop, for daily jobs, and Brazil Build for Cloud environment.

Techs used: React, Angular, Node, Express, jQuery, GraphQL, MongoDB

Rootstrap Software Engineer January 2011 - December 2012 (2 years) New York, NY, United States

• Used third-party API to put the data as time series and tabular format for local timestamp data manipulation and retrieval and storing it into MongoDB,

developed views and templates with MVC model's view controller and templating language to create a user-friendly Website interface.

Techs used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, PHP, Python

## Education

New York University

Bachelor of Computer Science, Computer Science · (2005 - 2010)